<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Dipal Bhavsar]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my description that will be used in the meta tags and important for search results]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 12:48:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[SharePoint Framework Overview]]></title><description><![CDATA[First off, let me welcome you in the world of SharePoint, client side development. Now a days, SharePoint Framework is much interesting…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Framework_OverView/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Framework_OverView/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;First off, let me welcome you in the world of SharePoint, client side development. Now a days, SharePoint Framework is much interesting since it has open wide range of offering with different technology stacks. This would be a big first step to learning the SharePoint Framework and I’m happy to help you on the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have taken a look at the Microsoft’s documentation, it has provided you a step wise process to learn how to start with the development starting with setting up the development environment. Here, probably we are repeating the same steps with wide information behind a purpose of the each step that covers installation, development, execution and deployment of SharePoint’s client side web-parts. So let’s start with overview and then gradually move which supportive NPM packages that need to be installed for the development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is SharePoint Framework?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft introduced the SharePoint Framework in May 2016. This is not only make client-side customization easier, but it includes APIs and dynamic ways of deploying.
Provides full support for client-side customization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, since beginning of SharePoint can satisfy basic collaboration and communication needs of organizations out of the box, soon after implementing a solution, many organizations may opt for going beyond the core functionality. For example, companies may want to modify dashboards and menus or integrate a SharePoint solution with other software or implement core branding, etc. All these changes can be implemented with customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint supports all kind of customization and integration with other systems. The new feature provides an ability to deploy a bundle that contains full fledged functionality that ease to develop and customize, same we could do for the previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Execution is current context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed web-parts will always run in the current web context. In previous versions, most of all the web parts usually runs in context of IFRAME which was overhead to the process and execution time.This means not only will they load faster, but they will run within the context of the current user and using the current connection in the browser.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Responsive &amp;#x26; accessible user interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed web parts are rendered in the current page DOM and not in an IFRAME, they will not have the same properties associated with them as IFRAMES have. One of the biggest benefits to this is that the customization will be responsive and accessible by nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Endless ability to access data from anywhere&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint provides data communication through it’s dedicated REST API within it’s lists and libraries. Apart from, it also flexible to fetch data from any product of Microsoft umbrella i.e. OneDrive, Exchange, Dynamic365, etc. through Microsoft Graph API. SharePoint also support to access data from other API’s too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Free to choose different development stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous version of SharePoint, it has elected to go with a very different development model for the SharePoint Framework customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional SharePoint developers are used to using tools like Visual Studio to create SharePoint solutions or add-ins. With the SharePoint Framework, Microsoft has elected to embrace and adopt what is commonly referred to as the modern web development stack and tool-chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach opens the platform up to more developers because it is not limited to Windows; the tools are cross-platform. You can use any text editor you prefer. Popular open source tools are used to solve different parts of the build tool-chain from project scaffolding, building, serving, packaging all the way to deploying. This includes tools like Yeoman, Gulp, and Webpack, runtime like Node.js, package managers like NPM and editors like Visual Studio Code or Sublime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Classic and modern experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating customization with the SharePoint Framework, you want to make sure you are not excluding your users from using them in legacy SharePoint sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the SharePoint Framework is that the customization you create will work not only in the new current modern pages, but they will also work in the traditional classic web part pages as well as publishing pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next section we will learn how SharePoint framework development is different from traditional development.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Conducting Effective Code Reviews]]></title><description><![CDATA[Code review is a process that enables peers and automated tools to check proposed changes to a codebase. The main goal of a code review is…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/ConductingEffectiveCodeReviews/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/ConductingEffectiveCodeReviews/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Code review is a process that enables peers and automated tools to check proposed changes to a codebase. The main goal of a code review is to catch potential issues, security problems, and bugs before they are introduced to the codebase and prevent them from causing problems in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, the code review can be fun. You try to hunt down well-disguised bugs before they hurt your production. You feel like a superhero defending your town every time you find a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most software developers are expected to participate in code reviews, and yet few are offered any training or guidance on conducting and participating in an effective code review. Participants attempt to find the most appropriate solution to a problem given the constraints of time, effort, and skills of all involved. But how do we have that conversation? What does an effective conversation look like? And what are the challenges of participating in a code review, and how can you overcome them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following useful literature could help to understand the purpose of code review and help to set up the process for conducting the effective code review with team members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://auth0.com/blog/conducting-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.auth0.com/blog/illustration/code-review-discussion.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting Effective Code Reviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/blog/how-to-conduct-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.prismic.io/www-static/287bb0dc-2d4f-41ac-b8e7-cc701e3e1d23_CodeReview_blog.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
How to Conduct Effective Code Reviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ltvco.com/engineering/conducting-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ltv-content.ltvco.com/1600x0/filters:format(jpeg)/filters:quality(70)/2019-11-21-code_review.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Code Review best practices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perforce.com/blog/qac/9-best-practices-for-code-review&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.perforce.com/sites/default/files/image/2018-12/image-blog-best-practices-code-reviews.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
9 Best Practices for Code Review&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Code review]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a code review page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a code review page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[About]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a technology page
This is my resume]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/about/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/about/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a technology page
This is my resume&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[About]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a technology page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting! I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/contact/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/contact/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a technology page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here’s a great quote from this Wikipedia on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_duck_egg&quot;&gt;salted duck eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A salted duck egg is a Chinese preserved food product made by soaking duck
eggs in brine, or packing each egg in damp, salted charcoal. In Asian
supermarkets, these eggs are sometimes sold covered in a thick layer of salted
charcoal paste. The eggs may also be sold with the salted paste removed,
wrapped in plastic, and vacuum packed. From the salt curing process, the
salted duck eggs have a briny aroma, a gelatin-like egg white and a
firm-textured, round yolk that is bright orange-red in color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 590px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMB/8QAFwEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEBf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABgik0dXC//8QAGRABAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACEhEy/9oACAEBAAEFAkqW2DlnRj73yf/EABcRAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREkH/2gAIAQMBAT8B1WX/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQL/2gAIAQIBAT8Bi6f/xAAbEAABBAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIRISIxMv/aAAgBAQAGPwK9GNocyS8hCj//xAAbEAADAQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABESEAMUGBof/aAAgBAQABPyGxNMfrLHmCDZmAzzvJJDjEQCHv/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABDIL//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERAP/aAAgBAwEBPxARhylZv//EABgRAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABESFR/9oACAECAQE/EFoktI//xAAdEAEBAAICAwEAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAxIWFBcYHh/9oACAEBAAE/EEbMLQ0fMHDVaPIXyI4pk4JUnWacNCtO8ojDE9TGIYES7/Jn/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Chinese Salty Egg&quot;
        title=&quot;Chinese Salty Egg&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/1c72d/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/a80bd/salty_egg.jpg 148w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/1c91a/salty_egg.jpg 295w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/1c72d/salty_egg.jpg 590w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/a8a14/salty_egg.jpg 885w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/fbd2c/salty_egg.jpg 1180w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg 2048w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to prevent downstream problems?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Recently, I moved into my new home. It was very exited moment moving from older home to new one for my family. My kids were also exited…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/How_to_prevent_downstream_problems/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/How_to_prevent_downstream_problems/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I moved into my new home. It was very exited moment moving from older home to new one for my family. My kids were also exited, rather focusing much more on transition, they focus much more on other exited things i.e. amenities, play area, swimming pool and much more – this is obvious, and we left them with their excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the possession, there is general process to check all accessories given by the builder i.e. test all lights/switched/plugs are working, sanitary-ware are in proper place and functioning, door locks with respective keys, etc. One of authorized person guide us very meticulously about all the resources they have fitted for us as per the commitment given during book the flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In during my observation of the new flat, I found some of the pipes under washbasin and kitchen sink were not straight. Instead the pipe from the drain goes down farther than necessary, curves right back up and then heads into the wall. The entire fitting looks like U-turn. This entire process was challenged my Physics knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting free from my transit and arranged require stuff, I Googled and found it is a P-Trap. That’s because it looks like a P turned on this side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do plumbers install P-traps? They must cost more to manufacture, so it increases their costs and time, which they may or may not be able to pass on to customers. They’re a little harder to install, so they cost the plumber time, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question curious me to get answered. So, why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plumbers install P-traps because they prevent downstream problems. A P-trap under your sink will trap some crud and debris that makes it into the sink. Without a P-trap, debris would flow farther into your pipes and be much harder to fix when it creates a clog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And good plumbers care about this even though they know they may not be the plumber to return to fix the problem. How smart they are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good plumbers care because they’re good plumbers. Installing a P-trap under your sink is simply the right thing to do because it prevents downstream problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a being software developer, should we behave the same way? Good team members care - not just about their own work but also about the work of everyone downstream of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a code is just a state of mind toward solving logical issue. Composing different patterns, best practices, considering different test cases and much more are value added during writing the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a code reviewer, I was recently helping a team incorporate more automated testing into their work. Some programmers, who viewed their job as nothing more than writing what they considered good code, balked at the idea of altering their code to make future testing easier. Code testability, they argued, was not their problem—it was the testers’ problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation came to a head during a sprint planning meeting, when the testers were giving some really large estimates for testing code that was going to take only a fraction of that amount of time to program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programmers were asked if they could do anything to make the code easier to test. And it turned out there were some things they could do, but some of the programmers didn’t want to do them because they felt it would make their code less elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had defined their jobs as merely writing good code. Who cared if that code was hard to test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my plumber had done that, I would have had a fully functional sink, perhaps for years. But eventually enough debris would have made it past where a P-trap should have been installed and deep into my plumbing. This would have led to an expensive—and easily avoidable—repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When team members accept responsibility for issues caused downstream of their work, that team is truly prepared to succeed with agile.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Code review]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a code review page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/test/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/test/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a code review page
This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>