<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Dipal Bhavsar]]></title><description><![CDATA[This site is developed using React, GatsBy, Bootstrap 4.5. Hosted in GitHub page. this site is intense to self learning and exploring different technologies.]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 18:01:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The importance of empty spaces in our Lives and Products]]></title><description><![CDATA[A hostel room with empty walls I love empty spaces. When I was in my 20s, I stayed in hostel for study for almost five years. The hostel had…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/The_importance_of_empty_space/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/The_importance_of_empty_space/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1538108149393-fbbd81895907?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;#x26;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;#x26;auto=format&amp;#x26;fit=crop&amp;#x26;w=650&amp;#x26;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;A hostel room with empty walls&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:9px&quot;&gt;Image courtesy of: unsplash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love empty spaces. When I was in my 20s, I stayed in hostel for study for almost five years. The hostel had all the basic furnishings but had nothing beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All room’s walls were completely bare—no paintings, posters or photographs. There were no knick-knacks or any other little decorations anywhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sparse as it was, I loved that hostel. In fact, I loved it more because of how empty it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love empty spaces because of constantly fill them up with different things. My office is full of posters, books, music, magazines, computers and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fill up our products, too. If people aren’t buying, we add a feature with the hope that will bring more customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a website, if there’s space in the nav bar, we come up with a new menu item. Then when all the empty space in the menu bar is full, we add dropdown menus and nested dropdown menus. Or we invent newer approaches like the three-line “hamburger” icon and put menu options there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do this within our lives, too. At least I do. I have backlogs of books to read, CDs to listen to, video training courses and movies to watch, and more. And if I ever get caught up on those, I have a list in OneNote of the next books, CDs, courses, and movies to buy so I can replenish my backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s difficult to find an empty space in my life. When one project finishes, another get started, and few more in pipeline. Sometimes it feels “suffocating”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s suffocating when the products we build fill every bit of empty space. It’s not that a product must only do one thing, but a product does not need to do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald Reinertsen has said that buyers choose between competing products on the basis of three of four key factors. Figure out what those factors are and make them great. Think about leaving out as much of the rest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, instead of engaging in different activities, now learning to find an empty space in my life. I’ve cut back a bit on travel. I’m eliminating or delegating work that I’m not uniquely qualified to do. This will let me bring more focus to the important things in my personal and work lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll consider doing the same. If we can get more empty space in our lives, it will help us succeed with agile—and other aspects of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Node.js, NPM & Package Managers, Part 5]]></title><description><![CDATA[So far we have covered about toolchain. Also, we understood it’s important in SPFx development. Here, we will explore further on Node.js and…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Package_manager/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Package_manager/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So far we have covered about toolchain. Also, we understood it’s important in SPFx development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we will explore further on Node.js and NPM. They are usually grouped together, and while I am doing that here in this installment, I personally see them as two very different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though, in the context of SharePoint Framework development, you don’t need to focus much at all on Node.js; just install it and move on. NPM is where you need to make sure that you are familiar with the commands including how to query, manage and upgrade new versions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Node.js needs to focus more. If you are working on MacOS, you should consider using a node version manager, or the node version manager: NVM, though it is not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;What is Node.js? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node.js, commonly just referred to as Node, is a cross-platform runtime that enables developers to create applications written in JavaScript that run on devices such as servers, desktops, laptops, embedded devices… lots of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 453px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/c4db534f91cf61594a64da14650cb719/2108e/nodejs.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 60.810810810810814%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAMCAYAAABiDJ37AAAACXBIWXMAAA7CAAAOwgEVKEqAAAACV0lEQVQoz22T3UtTcRjHzz/iSxemY5C7ELyRFGwd7Eq6KpU5MLtqd6ZXI1MQFYR5saDssgJfkMytIBVJXM7XTdOU1CNTa760hexszB23TztnHnPm91z8nt/D83x4eH7fI5BWKpUimUxqp/rpuVQqk/t3z8R2ux2Xy6XFap/eq0o4OztDlxprcBV0Dk6eQ9Umvbauro6GhgYtTiQSWf2CGsiyTDAYJEtp3m/5iKuKRCJYLBZsNttFTu3VwcLExARVVVUUFxfT19dHIq6wL0u8mu/g6dAjBmffEFdihEJhWltbMZlMGAwGmpubtcmdTiemWyZqHtbg9XoRCgoKsFqttLe3k5uXi2dqhpeLXTweEWkZauS+Q+Tzxid6e3opMhThcDgoLS3V4OPj4+Tl5tHyrIWyijLKb5cj5OTkMDw8TDQaJf9GPp5pD11jbdS/vcdzlw2xs4LBpQE62jqovFNJLBajurqapqYm3G43hTcLGfG8Z/H7IruBPQRRFPH5fJyenlJbW8vM9FcGfQPc7SnnybsHNL6uZzW4yuTYJCUlJdqURqOR/v5+JEnCbDZjNBi1dWk7PDk5uViuoija0lX5AkuMpME7R9us7K6wE5ZYW1+ju7Mbv9+f9UjOF05c7oyNBN1Luo+0509m7BGW/+DdmuFneB9/wM98YI6D6AGXvXtVwmWQbl49t3W4xcavdVz+UUZ9H/D88BA4DlzU6qfqP30ogWukmlmVdCQxtfGFue3ZNGyaj8tuQpFQFvC/Ca9L6sVxJc7CzgLf9lbSe1xm83Dz2l/xsv4Crwct/tvKWLIAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Node.JS&quot;
        title=&quot;Node.JS&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/c4db534f91cf61594a64da14650cb719/2108e/nodejs.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/c4db534f91cf61594a64da14650cb719/12f09/nodejs.png 148w,
/static/c4db534f91cf61594a64da14650cb719/e4a3f/nodejs.png 295w,
/static/c4db534f91cf61594a64da14650cb719/2108e/nodejs.png 453w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does this by hosting the Chromium project’s V8 JavaScript virtual machine. Chromium is the open-source browser project that Google’s Chrome browser is based on. It also includes APIs for interacting with the local device for things like file IO, environment variables, and networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main distributions of Node.js. The long-term support or LTS version is a version that has strict requirements for new features and updates. This is the version that many enterprises use because it’s not always changing and improving. It is also the version that Microsoft recommends for development with the SharePoint framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other is what they call the current version. This has the latest features added to Node.js. Eventually, these features will make it into the LTS version, but in current they are less mature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Why do you need Node.js? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the toolchain for development of SPFx built on Node.JS, so it require. This gives us the cross-platform aspect of SharePoint framework development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 453px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/751270144fe5e3cd5f416918aae587d9/2108e/npm.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 39.189189189189186%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAICAIAAAB2/0i6AAAACXBIWXMAAA7DAAAOwwHHb6hkAAABo0lEQVQY02O4Zm11zc7umo3NNVswAjFsQcgGxoWKwBhgket29vfT0hjeLFr09eLFL6dOfb9x48WkiTdcXb6cPPnl9Omv5859u3r1TmTkw+Li7zdvAgW/nj8PVAYiz569Gx19OzCQAaju////79av/7hr16eDB2/5+wG5///+fT6h/9fLV49KSp51dgAFvl2+/HLq1L9fvz7r6Pz95s2j4uJb/v4Mn48eBco9LCp8XFnx6fDhmz7eQO6/Hz8u62gDuY/Kyp62toJM37QR6Khfr19dMTL8duUKWLMf1OanjQ3POto/nzhx09cHaO3/P39ezZv358MHkM0dIJs/7t59OzTkz/t3N5wcf9y//6i8HGTz876+zyeO342OupeY8Ly391aAP0jz//9AP386cADIvZea8vn0qaetLdftbN+uWgm0+dXsWXciwm/5+DLcDgy4HRR4OyQYyL/uYH/Ty/PbpUtAncDgve7oABQESoHUBAcBbQapDAsFkeFhT6qqGP79/g1Ef3/8gLjtsp7uVXOzq2amVwwNPx8DBce/nz8hatDRn98Aa9RKKNWumzgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;NPM&quot;
        title=&quot;NPM&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/751270144fe5e3cd5f416918aae587d9/2108e/npm.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/751270144fe5e3cd5f416918aae587d9/12f09/npm.png 148w,
/static/751270144fe5e3cd5f416918aae587d9/e4a3f/npm.png 295w,
/static/751270144fe5e3cd5f416918aae587d9/2108e/npm.png 453w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is NPM? NPM is the package manager for Node.js. NPM is a node.js based tool that you use to acquire and manage packages within your projects. Some Node.js tools are also distributed using NPM. For instance, when you want to install a new version of the TypeScript compiler, you will run…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;NPM install -g typescript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tells NPM to install the package TypeScript globally. When you install something globally, it’s available anywhere in your environment. If you leave off that -g it is installed locally in the current working directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special note makes sure you are using NPM version 5 or higher. The reason for this is prior to version 5 (actually prior to version 3) create some issue in Windows OS. NPM version 3 flatted this and kept everything in a single folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Installing Node.js &amp; NPM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways you can get Node.js installed on your environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Follow instructions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/en/download/&quot;&gt;https://nodejs.org/en/download/&lt;/a&gt; for LTS.
The first option is to head to the Node.js website, download an installer for the latest LTS version for your platform and follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limitation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This works, but you will find at times you have to work with Node.js as an admin, either within an administrative command prompt in Windows or by prefixing any Node based commands with sudo on MacOS or Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The other limitation of this approach is you can only have one version of Node.js &amp;#x26; NPM installed at any time on your developer environment. Generally, that is not a big deal, it is just annoying at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Install using Node.js Version Manager (NVM)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other option that I prefer is to use the Node.js version manager or NVM. Once installed, this helps you acquire different versions of node and switch between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Node.js install you get has its own global package installation folder so you can have different globally installed versions between node runtime installs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also avoids admin command prompts because it installs the node runtime within your profile. Since you always have admin rights over your profile, you are effectively always running as admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like managing my Node.js installs using NVM because it lets me use the latest features but also get the flexibility of jumping between versions and trying new things out without impacting my current stable setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NVM for MacOS: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creationix/nvm&quot;&gt;https://github.com/creationix/nvm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NVM for Windows: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coreybutler/nvm-windows&quot;&gt;https://github.com/coreybutler/nvm-windows&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a version of NVM for both MacOS and Windows depending on your platform of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 529px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/8e36c0736fe420f27b12abd80155c4fd/67d6a/npm1.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 60.810810810810814%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAMCAIAAADtbgqsAAAACXBIWXMAAA7DAAAOwwHHb6hkAAACWklEQVQoz4WS3W/SUBjGTym0jNIPRlsKa8vhY7IBGwKOUVAYYw5C1H0Hs4zA5sIyzTbJFrdwgSZ6IUuWGL0yXnjt3dwy6BQyvdF/y1a9nT7nzZuTnJz83jzPC0bWXiw+8azv+0sV0YhjRtwMNCHaAc71MHyXE1+nhbYiHCuO38UdJ53tFHyTFfdvAWEszo2ludGEDYYtrgANbxgxTPuOAiC/SsHvC5GL5Xv9+t3eo/ne1mJvu9LfnbqsiL37nvd54IhOj08y8RQTV8hkjKBtuM5FEY08dBDz9xZyn9eq6t7W5UFdbdS7jcPO0fLZpr87J59kgK9YyywFpldCkzm7ctNIWRBgMAyIJFv0SB9yUbW8oT591m89/9La6O6WO9vVzk75vJ74uupqpwGiMwDKiCjrAzhOpYfknaj/bdb7cQZ+KoyeztcvGnvq4ZHabHWa9fPdytnjw04zrpYdLyeBO8LSLsomDUoRnhFoM0virJVgyAFgho2J4M9ytl/LfKtmr2r5q41kf1XprxWuNkM/HnpOcsAdczASb/c67V6ecAiD0Mb7XLE7t+OZKTE1whRlsiCRs5LWrQWJKsiUdpkVbSU4mJCAzy/THDvkcvqj8UAiyUERtTJWzoVbLIjBAP4tZ3iCHw4xEnQHgpJvmBJkpzdIC1AP26Dbfm1prxaWJ4RhI04hZh5QbkRbFBRBDYhupO4lch3VaMIALG7ml7gHFam0Yp+bJTi7SWci4L8yabsoK4VILhKZiQaTvnFlVPB6cZLGCRIjrBhJo7hZGwFF0T+J6sH+nQiYMOwXjBJ8Djfa5AwAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;NPM Version Manager&quot;
        title=&quot;NPM Version Manager&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/8e36c0736fe420f27b12abd80155c4fd/67d6a/npm1.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/8e36c0736fe420f27b12abd80155c4fd/12f09/npm1.png 148w,
/static/8e36c0736fe420f27b12abd80155c4fd/e4a3f/npm1.png 295w,
/static/8e36c0736fe420f27b12abd80155c4fd/67d6a/npm1.png 529w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing NVM and Node.js is very straightforward using the links I just provided. Personally, I’m a huge fan of NVM and use the versions listed above in both my MacOS laptop and Windows laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Additional Package Manager Options: Yarn &amp; PNPM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPM was the first package manager used to pull packages down from the NPM package registry at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org&quot;&gt;https://www.npmjs.org&lt;/a&gt;. This registry is the primary registry all Node.js projects and most client-side packages are pulled from. It’s replaced other registries such as Bower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPM maintained a hold on the package management space for a while, leaving developers to address its shortcomings around speed, consistency and version locking. Since competing package managers were introduced, specifically Yarn, NPM has stepped up its game and is on par for the most part with the others out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yarnpkg.com&quot;&gt;Yarn - https://yarnpkg.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yarn was created as a collaboration between Facebook and Google to address the shortcomings of NPM. The two biggest things it added was the concept of a lockfile and package cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The package cache helped eliminate the issue where each time you installed packages in a new project, instead of pulling a new copy from the NPM registry, Yarn would first check to see if you had already downloaded it in the past. If you had, it would skip the download process and instead just copy the package from the local cache into your project folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lockfile would ensure that each time packages were installed with yarn, it the same version you got last time would be downloaded. Before this concept was introduced, if you ran installed packages on a Monday with NPM, and someone installed them on the same project on Wednesday, there was no guarantee you would get the same versions of the packages because someone may have shipped an update between the two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pnpm.js.org&quot;&gt;PNPM - https://pnpm.js.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the newest one on the scene. It does everything the other two generators do in the sense of lockfiles and a package cache. However, it has one different characteristic…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of copying the packages from the cache to the project, it creates a hard link from the project’s node_modules folder to the folder in the package cache. This means your project folders are much smaller!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Which Package Manager Should You Use? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to consider the options and decide which one makes the most sense for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next section, we will further look over on Yeoman.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Advice on Whether You're Taking Too Long in Sprint Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Too many teams spend too much time in sprint planning. Here, let me try to clear how you can use the idea of only planning two-thirds of a…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/Team_taking_long_time_on_Sprint_planning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/Team_taking_long_time_on_Sprint_planning/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Too many teams spend too much time in sprint planning. Here, let me try to clear how you can use the idea of only planning two-thirds of a sprint’s tasks during the planning meeting to determine if your team is spending the right amount of time in its sprint planning meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what you do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few sprints, change nothing about sprint planning. But track how many tasks are identified during the planning meeting and how many tasks are added during the sprint. An added task will be something like, “Oops, we forgot this story also affects one of the reports.” Track that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tool makes this easy. But, if you’re using index cards or sticky notes, put a discreet dot on the paper such that the team doesn’t notice it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of each sprint, you’ll know something like your team did 58 total tasks, 12 of which were identified during the sprint. That means 46/58 or 79 percent were identified during the planning meeting. Do this for three sprints. You’ll see if that’s close to identifying two-thirds during the planning meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a team is averaging well above two thirds, compliment team members on their ability to plan and then cut the next meeting shorter. Tell them they are thinking too hard and taking planning too seriously. Save time by doing it faster and letting them get to work sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if they are averaging much less than two-thirds, explain that they will probably benefit from more time spent in sprint planning. Clarify that the goal isn’t a perfect set of tasks, but the improved understanding that comes from doing the planning. Then have the team spend a bit longer than in prior sessions until they start getting about two-thirds of tasks identified during planning meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this as a guideline for how long your sprint planning meetings should be will help your teams succeed with agile.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introduction - IdentityServer]]></title><description><![CDATA[IdentityServer4 is an OpenID Connect and OAuth 2.0 framework for ASP.NET Core. It enables the following features in your applications…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/IdentityServer/IdentityServer_Introduction/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/IdentityServer/IdentityServer_Introduction/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;IdentityServer4 is an OpenID Connect and OAuth 2.0 framework for ASP.NET Core.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It enables the following features in your applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Authentication as a Service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centralized login logic and workflow for all of your applications (web, native, mobile, services). IdentityServer is an officially &lt;a href=&quot;https://openid.net/certification/&quot;&gt;certified&lt;/a&gt; implementation of OpenID Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Single Sign-on / Sign-out&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single sign-on (and out) over multiple application types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Access Control for APIs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issue access tokens for APIs for various types of clients, e.g. server to server, web applications, SPAs and native/mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Federation Gateway&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for external identity providers like Azure Active Directory, Google, Facebook etc. This shields your applications from the details of how to connect to these external providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Focus on Customization&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part - many aspects of IdentityServer can be customized to fit your needs. Since IdentityServer is a framework and not a boxed product or a SaaS, you can write code to adapt the system the way it makes sense for your scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mature Open Source&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IdentityServer uses the permissive Apache 2 license that allows building commercial products on top of it. It is also part of the .NET Foundation which provides governance and legal backing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more useful detail &lt;a href =&quot;&quot;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SPFx Development with Node.js and TypeScript, Part 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[In previous section we have covered what tools and frameworks were required to do SharePoint Framework development. We should not stop here…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Development_Node_TypeScript/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Development_Node_TypeScript/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In previous section we have covered what tools and frameworks were required to do SharePoint Framework development. We should not stop here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer could have different categories, some of them are having little or some experience with client side technologies or tools, some of them are having core .Net, Java or I say, strong object oriented technology experience or some of them are having mix of technologies experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore what other tools are required in order to develop SharePoint client side webpart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will go deep about tools and technologies. I also drew some parallels to the tools you are familiar with as a traditional SharePoint or .NET developer. In this section, I want to emphasis about each of the different components that make up the build toolchain - let’s make it simplify.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why do we need all this stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft could have done a much better job in explaining this from the start, but they didn’t nor have they done a good job of clearing it up. So in this installment, I want to take a minute and tell you what you need to know and what you can ignore as part of this build &amp;#x26; development toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start by saying you do not need to become an expert or well versed in all these things. While you may need them, some you can install &amp;#x26; ignore they are even used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, you only need to be understand how to use NPM and TypeScript. You need to get familiar with TypeScript as that is the language you will be writing and as for NPM, you need to get familiar with it as that’s the tool you will use when you want to update your toolchain as well as find, install and update external libraries you are going to use in your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presently, you don’t need to worry about the things like Node.js, Yeoman, Gulp, and Webpack. Sure, you can learn a lot about them, but you can get by just fine with just installing them and letting the tools Microsoft provides to run &amp;#x26; configure them for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You NEED to know NPM and TypeScript
You need to know NPM and how it works for one simple reason: you will use this in every single project to acquire, manage and upgrade dependencies in your SharePoint Framework project. It has become the standard for reusable package and Node.js package distribution for web developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure we have NuGet, but it wasn’t until recently that NuGet was supported off a Windows environment… and that support is quite limited at that. Plus, NuGet can only handle package distribution. There is no concept of installing global utilities in NuGet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So because you will use NPM in every single project, I think you need to learn the commands.
Furthermore, you do need to learn TypeScript. OK, you don’t have to learn TypeScript, but you really should… at least in my opinion. It’s sort of like back in the day when every code sample Microsoft was shipping early on was C# and all the VB developers were constantly asking for VB.NET samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft will continue to use TypeScript as their language of choice for client-side development so you might as well get familiar with it if you are going to work in the SharePoint Framework space. But if you want to stick with pure JavaScript, you can do that too just tag things with any type, configure the TypeScript compiler to not report errors and warnings on certain things or just ignore them when you compile as all JavaScript is valid TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install, but then essentially ignore Node.js, Gulp, Yeoman, and Webpack
Really? Yup! Here’s why: first, the only reason you need Node.js is that all the other tools (NPM, Gulp, Yeoman, Webpack and the TypeScript compiler) are all built on Node.js. Therefore you need it to run these tools. But once installed, you don’t care about it anymore. You don’t write a Node.js program at any time… you just install it and forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gulp, as you see, is used to run tasks like building or deploying code. While you can learn to build your own custom tasks, you do not need to. Microsoft has given you all the tasks you need for most SharePoint Framework development so you just need to know how to type the command to get it going. For instance, to start the local workbench environment, just type gulp serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeoman is very much like Gulp in this sense. You need it to scaffold up your projects, but you do not need to know how to write your own generators. Instead, you just need to know how to run the generator which can be boiled down to three keystrokes at the command prompt: yo&lt;enter&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Webpack, I’m going to explain more detail how this is used, but this is by far the easiest to ignore. Why? Because first, you never even install it! Microsoft’s default setup is to include a copy of Webpack in every single project scaffolding. Now, I’m not saying that’s a good practice… I’m not sure it is, but I’m not saying it. ;) Webpack needs a configuration file which is created by Microsoft’s build process in memory. Therefore you never see it, you never call it, and Microsoft does all the configuration of it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this has cleared up some things that were a bit intimidating or gave you pause. In future installments, I’ll look at each of these things in a bit more detail and explain why you need them, how you install them and how they work. We will start tomorrow with Node.js &amp;#x26; NPM. See you then!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SPFx Development Toolchain Comparison, Part 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the last session, we have covered comparision of the development and deployment story for customizations created using the SharePoint…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Development_Toolchain_Approach/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SPFx_Development_Toolchain_Approach/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In the last session, we have covered comparision of the development and deployment story for customizations created using the SharePoint Framework to those using a more traditional SharePoint approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I will provide an overview of the SharePoint Framework development toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will need is a SharePoint developer tenant. This is a tenant in SharePoint online in office 365. This environment also has a copy of the SharePoint workbench that you can use to test our web parts out as well. The workbench is a locally hosted page that can host your SharePoint client-side web parts. Using this page you can develop and test locally, all without a full SharePoint deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at the different tools you will need, but in doing so, let’s compare them to what you are used to using if you are coming from the traditional SharePoint or .NET development world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 572px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/cb41567a00b98a75b7710a2d207aee70/a805e/toolchain.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 36.486486486486484%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAHCAIAAACHqfpvAAAACXBIWXMAAA7DAAAOwwHHb6hkAAABRElEQVQY001QPW/CMBTMn+zepT+pa7cuFQyoHVhgoJVaVTBUVIWEFAExIYE4Id+On+30kqnWk3znd/d8tqWUJqWN0UT6e5X/2IVtl7t9zXzhuJW7BWjsTeG4gvkkpW7/LWuxDadfm+B0Anl24ncv5mWmWhMFcegHCY+yJEUrCBhje4DlcjmZTMIw7MxSadFIrbuRaa1yQXUjjWllQ3laJjwrsgqtI/OPRx9gtVrNZrPocunMrTGkkF2jDNID9LQjrSHCoF5gDEpi7wOjK4ms7rnaQN1IXKYaAKWop5I6DwAk+BPTHatayooUwkqSVlHm7q/DeYR5Bv7LWZxDLWrQ4hrNp2MA+1yO1xy1juq2KtPXN2TLK7Lmi4/bu5unwSNENY/YcOANB6V3APV325eHe4BDUn4e+MJL9qloiyIejQRpFlz/AMEnh9g3QFTEAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Development Toolchain Comparison&quot;
        title=&quot;Development Toolchain Comparison&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/cb41567a00b98a75b7710a2d207aee70/a805e/toolchain.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/cb41567a00b98a75b7710a2d207aee70/12f09/toolchain.png 148w,
/static/cb41567a00b98a75b7710a2d207aee70/e4a3f/toolchain.png 295w,
/static/cb41567a00b98a75b7710a2d207aee70/a805e/toolchain.png 572w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 572px) 100vw, 572px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional Microsoft way of doing development is building on the .NET Framework. This is the runtime that knows how to run the programs.
Node.js addresses this need. A lot of the tools in the modern web development world are built on top of Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;NPM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building .NET applications, we use a tool called NuGet to acquire prebuilt packages for use within our application.
In the Node world, we use a tool called NPM that does the same thing. We will use this to get packages our customizations need like Angular, jQuery or other useful libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Yeoman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio is Microsoft’s integrated development environment. When we want to create a new project, we use Visual Studio’s project templates to create the file &amp;#x26; folder scaffolding for the project.
With the SharePoint Framework, you can use any editor you want. But to get the folder &amp;#x26; file scaffolding created for the project we use a tool called Yeoman. You can install different project generators for Yeoman. Microsoft provides one for SharePoint client-side web parts that we will use as the starting point for our new project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TypeScript is a strongly typed, object oriented, compiled language. It was designed by Anders Hejlsberg (designer of C#) at Microsoft. TypeScript is both a language and a set of tools. TypeScript is a typed superset of JavaScript compiled to JavaScript. In other words, TypeScript is JavaScript plus some additional features.
SharePoint client-side development tools are built using TypeScript classes, modules, and interfaces. You can use these to build robust client-side web parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started with TypeScript, see the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/tutorial.html&quot;&gt;TypeScript Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/play/index.html&quot;&gt;TypeScript Playground&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/handbook/basic-types.html&quot;&gt;TypeScript Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Gulp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you know when you build a project in Visual Studio, some process kicks off to compile the project, maybe it manually starts up another process with your app in it and attaches a debugger? That’s not Visual Studio doing that, that’s Visual Studio calling MSBuild. Someone created tasks for MSBuild using an XML syntax what to do such as compile the project, copy the files from here to there and fire up a process followed by attaching the debugger.
The tool Gulp does the same thing. It allows you to write tasks using JavaScript and then tell Gulp to run those tasks for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;Webpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This comparison is not exact, but you’ll get the point. With a traditional SharePoint project, you compile the project files into an executable or a DLL.
In the JavaScript world, we have a similar process where we want to merge multiple files into a single bigger file for performance &amp;#x26; manageability. The tool Microsoft selected for the SharePoint Framework is Webpack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, we have covered a lot, it’s actually pretty simple, everything is free and does not require some big install. With a typical broadband connection or connecting mobile data, you can be up and running in 10 minutes or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next section, we will focus on what we need.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SharePoint Development Patterns, Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[In previous section, I explained about SharePoint Framework. In this post, I am going to take a look at different patterns available for…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Development_Patterns/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Development_Patterns/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:30:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In previous section, I explained about SharePoint Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to take a look at different patterns available for SharePoint development and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s get started and look at the different development, customization and extensibility options we have in SharePoint today. Since Microsoft has introduced this new SharePoint Framework model, they have not deprecated or removed any of the previous options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 25px;&quot;&gt;Development and Deployment in the SharePoint Framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explore the SharePoint Framework a bit more, then compare it to each of the other options and how they differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s first start by looking at the SharePoint Framework. SharePoint Framework customizations execute within the client. They are script-based, not compiled and thus they run in the context of the current page. This is also the only way to customize SharePoint’s modern pages in a supported way.
Because SharePoint Framework based customizations run in the context of the current page and not in some IFRAME, they are responsive and accessible and by nature, mobile friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customizations deployed for use with the SharePoint Framework are uploaded to the tenant’s app catalog site making the customizations available across any site within the tenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the initial release, the only thing developers could build with the SharePoint Framework are client-side web parts. However, later, Microsoft introduced extensions. These provided parity with some existing customization options we had in previous models. They include things like application customizers (aka script link &amp;#x26; delegate controls), field customizers (aka client-side rendering or CSR and JSLink) and command sets (aka custom actions). Recentrly, Microsoft also has announce one more capability as Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look at each of the other types of SharePoint development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 25px;&quot;&gt;Development &amp; Deployment with traditional Farm Solutions&lt;/p&gt;
 
Now let’s compare the SharePoint Framework to the farm or full-trust solutions.
&lt;table border=1 style=&quot;width:95%&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;SharePoint Framework&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Farm Solutions&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Server-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Render and execute in page context&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fully server side execution&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only way to costomize modern pages&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only supported on-premises environment&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open source cross-platform tooling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Built in Visual Studio on Windows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Support first &amp; third party development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to tenant or site &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to farm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Limited to creating client-side web parts, UI extentions and Libraries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Build web parts, timer jobs, event receiver, features receivers, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm solutions are typically comprised of compiled code that runs on the .NET Framework. They also consist of some amount of declarative markup, specifically XML, that tells SharePoint under what conditions the code should run. They are deployed using solution packages, *.WSP files, and features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm solutions, because they run on the server in the context of the SharePoint farm process, have full access to the SharePoint server-side API. Therefore developers can use these types of solutions to do anything supported by the API with custom code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because farm solutions are fully trusted customizations or highly trusted solutions, they are not permitted in hosted SharePoint environments such as SharePoint Online in Office 365. As such, they are limited to on-premises deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again, due to the server-side and full-trust nature of these types of customizations, farm solutions are almost exclusively built using Visual Studio by developers who are on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm solutions are scoped to the entire farm, well they can be scoped all the way up to the entire SharePoint farm, but depending on the customizations in the farm solution, they can be scoped at the web application, site collection or as granular as an individual site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm solutions are the core of all types of customizations going way back to the beginning in SharePoint. This means we use them to create server-side web parts, timer jobs, event receivers, feature receivers and other sorts of controls. These are all things the SharePoint Framework does not have the ability to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 25px;&quot;&gt;Development &amp; Deployment with Sandboxed Solutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=1 style=&quot;width:95%&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;SharePoint Framework&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Sendbox Solutions&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Server-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Render and execute in page context&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only way to costomize modern pages&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Declarative only solutions available in SharePoint OnLine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open source cross-platform tooling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Built in Visual Studio on Windows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Support first &amp; third party development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Responsive, accessible &amp; mobile friendly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to tenant or site &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to site collection&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Limited to creating client-side web parts, UI extentions and Libraries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Build features &amp; declarative solutions&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
After farm solutions came sandboxed solutions, introduced by Microsoft to let developers create server-side compiled solutions run in a hosted environment.
&lt;p&gt;Initially sandboxed solutions, like farm solutions which they were derived from, consisted of both declarative and compiled code. The idea was to give customers a way to customize &amp;#x26; extend their site collections without the full trust risks from farm solutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this changed over time to the tune that Microsoft removed support for compiled-code sandboxed solutions in SharePoint Online in Office 365. You can still do declarative sandboxed solutions in Office 365, just no managed code. Also, like farm solutions, sandboxed solutions are created using the Office and SharePoint developer tools Microsoft offers as an extension to Visual Studio, the version of Visual Studio proper that runs on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, like farm solutions, sandboxed solutions are created using the Office and SharePoint developer tools Microsoft offers as an extension to Visual Studio, the version of Visual Studio proper that runs on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandboxed solutions are scoped to the site collection they are installed and activated within. Unlike farm solutions that can be activated at a farm or web application scope, the widest scope possible for a sandboxed solution is a site collection. This is true for declarative solutions today as well as when we could still do compiled code based solutions when they were supported in SharePoint Online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to do a lot more with sandboxed solutions when compiled code was supported however, isn’t supported anymore.
Therefore, sandboxed solutions can be used today to provision declarative solutions such as site columns, content types, list templates and instances. We can also use them to provision files like ASPX pages with no code in them as well as JavaScript, CSS and image files to deploy custom client-side customizations to a SharePoint site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 25px;&quot;&gt;Development &amp; Deployment with Add-ins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=1 style=&quot;width:95%&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;SharePoint Framework&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;SharePoint Add-Ins&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client or Server side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Render and execute in page context&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client side API&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only way to costomize modern pages&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open source cross-platform tooling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Execution context externalized from SharePoint using IFrame&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Support first &amp; third party development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Build with Visual Studio on Windows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Responsive, accessible &amp; mobile friendly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to tenant or site &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to tenant and site&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Limited to creating client-side web parts, UI extentions and Libraries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Build web parts, remote event receivers, workflows and more&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
After solutions came SharePoint Add-ins, initially called apps. 
&lt;p&gt;These are available in two flavors, the SharePoint Hosted Add-in and the Provider Hosted Add-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;b&gt;SharePoint Hosted Add-ins&lt;/b&gt;, they run exclusively within a client-side context. Any custom business logic has to be implemented using JavaScript as the files deployed to SharePoint while stored in SharePoint, are not run on the server. They are rendered in the client and run there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of &lt;b&gt;Provider Hosted Add-ins&lt;/b&gt;, these are more open-ended. The developer, or provider, of the add-in, deploys a web application external to SharePoint and thus, can use any web development techniques at their disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the type of add-in you create, any time your add-in needs to communicate with SharePoint will do it using one of the client-side APIs Microsoft has included in SharePoint; either the CSOM or robust REST API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an add-in is manifested within a SharePoint site as a client part, it is done so using an IFRAME. This is due to the fact the add-in execution context is externalized from SharePoint, running either in the provider hosted web application or within the special SharePoint site that hosts the SharePoint Hosted add-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint add-ins were typically built by developers using Visual Studio on Windows. This is because Microsoft only created extensions for Visual Studio with designers for configuring an add-in and creating the add-in package file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Provider Hosted Add-ins could be authored using any technology for any hosting platform, we saw most developers using the Microsoft stack and host their provider hosted add-in web applications using IIS web servers on-premises or in Microsoft Azure websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you, as the developer, package up a SharePoint add-in, you take the resulting package file and upload it to the SharePoint tenant’s app catalog. Once this is done, the SharePoint add-in can then be installed within any SharePoint site in that tenant associated with that app catalog. Therefore, it is scoped to the tenant as far as where it can be used, but its functionality is scoped to the site to where it was installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can use SharePoint add-ins to create web parts, but not web parts the way we used to with solutions. Instead, these are created as web pages that are surfaced within SharePoint sites using IFRAMES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can also create event custom workflows, declarative workflows based on Workflow Manager and deploy those with add-ins. While the logic and implementation are hosted in a web application external from SharePoint, add-ins can also register remote event receivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 25px;&quot;&gt;Development &amp; Deployment with JavaScript Injection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=1 style=&quot;width:95%;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; &gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;SharePoint Framework&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;JavaScript Injection&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client-side execution model&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Render and execute in page context&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Client side API&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Only way to costomize modern pages&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Open source cross-platform tooling&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Build/implement with any build toolchain&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Support first &amp; third party development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Responsive, accessible &amp; mobile friendly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to tenant or site &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scoped to SharePoint page&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Limited to creating client-side web parts, UI extentions and Libraries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Implemented manually, no automated deployment story&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
The last type of customization is JavaScript injection which is used to customize existing SharePoint sites. Developers can use the content editor web part or more recently the script editor web part to get the customizations onto the page.
&lt;p&gt;Because of the very nature of JavaScript injection, these customizations will always execute within a client-side context. This means they leverage the user’s context and are rendered in the native page DOM.
By extension, because JavaScript injection involves client-side based development, these customizations have can leverage the client-side API, using either the CSOM or REST API, to leverage SharePoint data in the customizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript injection does not involve specific developer tools. All developers need is a text editor and a way to upload the files to SharePoint. This is typically done using the browser, so developers are free to use any tool that they use to create their customizations when leveraging JavaScript injection.
These customizations are added to each SharePoint page on a page-by-page basis that means that these customizations are scoped to a specific page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because JavaScript injection customizations are done on a manual basis, typically there’s no packaging model, there’s no deployment model, and there’s no provisioning model that Microsoft provides.
Sure, SharePoint developers can build some sort of a customized solution but for the most part, these are usually customizations that are implemented on a case-by-case basis and they usually are implemented manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today,  we looked at the previous options for SharePoint customization and extensibility and we compared them to the SharePoint Framework. By now you should have an idea where the SharePoint Framework fits, and where it doesn’t fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next post, we will go through SharePoint Framework development toolchain.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SharePoint Framework Overview, Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[First off, let me welcome you in the world of SharePoint, client side development. Now a days, SharePoint Framework is much interesting…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Framework_OverView/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/sharepoint/SharePoint_Framework_OverView/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;First off, let me welcome you in the world of SharePoint, client side development. Now a days, SharePoint Framework is much interesting since it has open wide range of offering with different technology stacks. This would be a big first step to learning the SharePoint Framework and I’m happy to help you on the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have taken a look at the Microsoft’s documentation, it has provided you a step wise process to learn how to start with the development starting with setting up the development environment. Here, probably we are repeating the same steps with wide information behind a purpose of the each step that covers installation, development, execution and deployment of SharePoint’s client side web-parts. So let’s start with overview and then gradually move which supportive NPM packages that need to be installed for the development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 30px;&quot;&gt;What is SharePoint Framework?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft introduced the SharePoint Framework in May 2016. This is not only make client-side customization easier, but it includes APIs and dynamic ways of deploying.
Provides full support for client-side customization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, since beginning of SharePoint can satisfy basic collaboration and communication needs of organizations out of the box, soon after implementing a solution, many organizations may opt for going beyond the core functionality. For example, companies may want to modify dashboards and menus or integrate a SharePoint solution with other software or implement core branding, etc. All these changes can be implemented with customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint supports all kind of customization and integration with other systems. The new feature provides an ability to deploy a bundle that contains full fledged functionality that ease to develop and customize, same we could do for the previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px;&quot;&gt;Execution is current context&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed web-parts will always run in the current web context. In previous versions, most of all the web parts usually runs in context of IFRAME which was overhead to the process and execution time.This means not only will they load faster, but they will run within the context of the current user and using the current connection in the browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px;&quot;&gt;Responsive &amp; accessible user interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed web parts are rendered in the current page DOM and not in an IFRAME, they will not have the same properties associated with them as IFRAMES have. One of the biggest benefits to this is that the customization will be responsive and accessible by nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px;&quot;&gt;Endless ability to access data from anywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint provides data communication through it’s dedicated REST API within it’s lists and libraries. Apart from, it also flexible to fetch data from any product of Microsoft umbrella i.e. OneDrive, Exchange, Dynamic365, etc. through Microsoft Graph API. SharePoint also support to access data from other API’s too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px;&quot;&gt;Free to choose different development stack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous version of SharePoint, it has elected to go with a very different development model for the SharePoint Framework customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional SharePoint developers are used to using tools like Visual Studio to create SharePoint solutions or add-ins. With the SharePoint Framework, Microsoft has elected to embrace and adopt what is commonly referred to as the modern web development stack and tool-chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach opens the platform up to more developers because it is not limited to Windows; the tools are cross-platform. You can use any text editor you prefer. Popular open source tools are used to solve different parts of the build tool-chain from project scaffolding, building, serving, packaging all the way to deploying. This includes tools like Yeoman, Gulp, and Webpack, runtime like Node.js, package managers like NPM and editors like Visual Studio Code or Sublime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px;&quot;&gt;Classic and modern experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating customization with the SharePoint Framework, you want to make sure you are not excluding your users from using them in legacy SharePoint sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the SharePoint Framework is that the customization you create will work not only in the new current modern pages, but they will also work in the traditional classic web part pages as well as publishing pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next section we will learn how SharePoint framework development is different from traditional development.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Conducting Effective Code Reviews]]></title><description><![CDATA[Code review is a process that enables peers and automated tools to check proposed changes to a codebase. The main goal of a code review is…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/ConductingEffectiveCodeReviews/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/technology/ConductingEffectiveCodeReviews/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Code review is a process that enables peers and automated tools to check proposed changes to a codebase. The main goal of a code review is to catch potential issues, security problems, and bugs before they are introduced to the codebase and prevent them from causing problems in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, the code review can be fun. You try to hunt down well-disguised bugs before they hurt your production. You feel like a superhero defending your town every time you find a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most software developers are expected to participate in code reviews, and yet few are offered any training or guidance on conducting and participating in an effective code review. Participants attempt to find the most appropriate solution to a problem given the constraints of time, effort, and skills of all involved. But how do we have that conversation? What does an effective conversation look like? And what are the challenges of participating in a code review, and how can you overcome them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following useful literature could help to understand the purpose of code review and help to set up the process for conducting the effective code review with team members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://auth0.com/blog/conducting-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.auth0.com/blog/illustration/code-review-discussion.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting Effective Code Reviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/blog/how-to-conduct-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.prismic.io/www-static/287bb0dc-2d4f-41ac-b8e7-cc701e3e1d23_CodeReview_blog.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
How to Conduct Effective Code Reviews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ltvco.com/engineering/conducting-effective-code-reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ltv-content.ltvco.com/1600x0/filters:format(jpeg)/filters:quality(70)/2019-11-21-code_review.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Code Review best practices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perforce.com/blog/qac/9-best-practices-for-code-review&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.perforce.com/sites/default/files/image/2018-12/image-blog-best-practices-code-reviews.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:150px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
9 Best Practices for Code Review&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to prevent downstream problems?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Recently, I moved into my new home. It was very exited moment moving from older home to new one for my family. My kids were also exited…]]></description><link>https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/How_to_prevent_downstream_problems/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.dipalbhavsar.com/agile/How_to_prevent_downstream_problems/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I moved into my new home. It was very exited moment moving from older home to new one for my family. My kids were also exited, rather focusing much more on transition, they focus much more on other exited things i.e. amenities, play area, swimming pool and much more – this is obvious, and we left them with their excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the possession, there is general process to check all accessories given by the builder i.e. test all lights/switched/plugs are working, sanitary-ware are in proper place and functioning, door locks with respective keys, etc. One of authorized person guide us very meticulously about all the resources they have fitted for us as per the commitment given during book the flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In during my observation of the new flat, I found some of the pipes under washbasin and kitchen sink were not straight. Instead the pipe from the drain goes down farther than necessary, curves right back up and then heads into the wall. The entire fitting looks like U-turn. This entire process was challenged my Physics knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting free from my transit and arranged require stuff, I Googled and found it is a P-Trap. That’s because it looks like a P turned on this side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do plumbers install P-traps? They must cost more to manufacture, so it increases their costs and time, which they may or may not be able to pass on to customers. They’re a little harder to install, so they cost the plumber time, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question curious me to get answered. So, why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plumbers install P-traps because they prevent downstream problems. A P-trap under your sink will trap some crud and debris that makes it into the sink. Without a P-trap, debris would flow farther into your pipes and be much harder to fix when it creates a clog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And good plumbers care about this even though they know they may not be the plumber to return to fix the problem. How smart they are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good plumbers care because they’re good plumbers. Installing a P-trap under your sink is simply the right thing to do because it prevents downstream problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a being software developer, should we behave the same way? Good team members care - not just about their own work but also about the work of everyone downstream of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a code is just a state of mind toward solving logical issue. Composing different patterns, best practices, considering different test cases and much more are value added during writing the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a code reviewer, I was recently helping a team incorporate more automated testing into their work. Some programmers, who viewed their job as nothing more than writing what they considered good code, balked at the idea of altering their code to make future testing easier. Code testability, they argued, was not their problem—it was the testers’ problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation came to a head during a sprint planning meeting, when the testers were giving some really large estimates for testing code that was going to take only a fraction of that amount of time to program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programmers were asked if they could do anything to make the code easier to test. And it turned out there were some things they could do, but some of the programmers didn’t want to do them because they felt it would make their code less elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had defined their jobs as merely writing good code. Who cared if that code was hard to test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my plumber had done that, I would have had a fully functional sink, perhaps for years. But eventually enough debris would have made it past where a P-trap should have been installed and deep into my plumbing. This would have led to an expensive—and easily avoidable—repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When team members accept responsibility for issues caused downstream of their work, that team is truly prepared to succeed with agile.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>